so let's look at the solution to our
mesh versus bus throughput quiz where we
had four cores
with a totally random and even
distribution of traffic among the cores
we are given what each core is sending
we are getting what the bus can do and
what the link in a mesh can do and now
we are asked how much faster is it
on the bus versus on the mesh our bus
cannot sustain the 40 million messages
per second
that the cores are trying to give it
so the cores are really going to slow
down to half of their speed so that the
bus bandwidth demand matches what it can
provide
so on the bus we get 2x the execution
time that each core is capable of
providing on the mesh we can support 20
million messages per second per link
so now the question is do our links get
saturated so let's see what we get on a
mesh like this in terms of traffic each
quarter is generating 10 million
messages 3.3 million are going to each
other core
so of the 10 million messages sent here
one third are going to this score one
third are going through this link and
then one third are going here let's say
that one sixth go this way one sixth go
this way so this link will be used for
one sixth of the messages sent by this
score and this one for another one sixth
and then we add 1 6 to each of these
which brings us to one half of 10
million messages so now we are done with
this score what happens from this score
same thing this link gets one half of
the messages one third are going here
one 6 are going here
so this link suffers one half of this
traffic again now this link gets
one half of the traffic from this core
and these two links get one sixth each
and now we're done with this score now
what happens when this score is sending
one half of the messages go this way one
half going go this way
one sixth of them go through this link
and one six go through this link done
with this score and finally this score
sends messages half here have here
and then one sixth here
and one sixth here now we're done with
this course so as you can see our links
are actually evenly used
each of them gets two times one-half
plus two-sixths so we get
one and one-third
times
the traffic generated by one core that
was what the one-half was off the
traffic from one core is 10 million
messages a second so we're really
getting 10
plus 3.3 so this is 13.3 million of
messages per second which is available
on our mesh so the mesh doesn't slow
down the processors
so really the speed up of using the mesh
versus the bus
is two because the bus requires the
cores to slow down so that
it can support the traffic that they're
generating
while the mesh allows the cores to
proceed at full speed at 10 million
messages per second and still has some
traffic left over
if we went to a larger network than four
cores the bus would have to
proportionally slow down while the mesh
would get more links
and it will be a while until any of the
mesh links become saturated so clearly
the mesh is far superior to the bus in
terms of the traffic it can support when
we go to more course